<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4.1/metadata.xsd">
		
	<identifier identifierType="DOI">10.20350/digitalCSIC/8972</identifier>
	<rightsList><rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"/></rightsList>
	<alternateIdentifiers><alternateIdentifier alternateIdentifierType="Handle">http://hdl.handle.net/10261/192622</alternateIdentifier></alternateIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ruiz, M., Díaz, J., Pedreira, D., Gallart, J., and Pulgar, J. A. (2017). Crustal structure of the North Iberian continental margin from seismic refraction/wide-angle reflection profiles. Tectonophysics 717, 65-82. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tecto.2017.07.008</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Fernández-Viejo, G., Pulgar, J.A., Gallastegui, J., and Quintana, L. (2012). The Fossil Accretionary Wedge of the Bay of Biscay: Critical Wedge Analysis on Depth-Migrated Seismic Sections and Geodynamical Implications. The Journal of Geology, vol. 120. http://dx.doi.org/10.1086/664789</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Roca, E., Muñoz, J.A., Ferrer, O., and Ellouz, N. (2011). The role of the Bay of Biscay Mesozoic extensional structure in the configuration of the Pyrenean orogen: Constraints from the MARCONI deep seismic reflection survey. Tectonics, vol. 30, TC2001. http://dx.doi.org/10.1029/2010TC002735</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Fernández-Viejo, G., Gallastegui, J., Pulgar, J.A., and Gallart, J. (2011). The MARCONI reflection seismic data: A view into the eastern part of the Bay of Biscay. Tectonophysics, vol. 508, n. 1-4, pp. 34-41. DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tecto.2010.06.020</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ferrer, O., Roca, E., Benjumea, B., Muñoz, J. A., Ellouz, N. (2008). The deep seismic reflection MARCONI-3 profile: Role of extensional Mesozoic structure during the Pyrenean contractional deformation at the eastern part of the Bay of Biscay. Marine and Petroleum Geology, vol. 25, n. 8, pp. 714-730. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2008.06.002</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ruiz, M., 2007. Caracterització estructural i sismotectònica de la litosfera en el domini Pirenaico-Cantàbric a partir de mètodes de sísmica activa i passiva. Univ. Barcelona: pp. 1–354 978846912784 (PhD Thesis). Handle: http://hdl.handle.net/10803/1923</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Gallart, J., Pulgar, J.A., Muñoz, J. A., and the MARCONI Team (2004). Integrated studies of the lithospheric structure and geodynamics of the North Iberian continental margin: the MARCONI project. Geophysical Research Abstracts, vol. 6, 04196.  1607-7962/gra/EGU04-A-04196</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Pulgar, J.A., Gallart, J., Fernández-Viejo, G., Gallastegui, J., Benjumea, B., Bartolomé, R., Rubio, E., Fernández-Baniela, F., Ferrer, O., and the MARCONI Team (2004). Structure of the southeastern continental margin of the Bay of Biscay: results from MARCONI deep seismic reflection profiles. Geophysical Research Abstracts, vol. 6, 04411.  1607-7962/gra/EGU04-A-04411</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Pulgar, J.A., Gallart, J., Fernández-Viejo, G., Gallastegui, J., Benjumea, B., Bartolomé, R., Ruiz, M., Fernández-Baniela, F., Ferrer, O., and the MARCONI Team (2004). Structure and tectonic evolution of the Cantabrian Margin of the Bay of Biscay: results from MARCONI multichannel seismic data. 11th International Symposium on deep structures of the continents and their margins: results from reflection, refraction and teleseismic seismology, Seismix 2004, Quebec, Canadá</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ferrer, O., Benjumea, B., Roca, E., Muñoz, J.A., Fernández, F., García, J., and the MARCONI Team (2004). The continental margin structure of the eastern part of the Bay of Biscay: the role of extensional Mesozoic structure during the later contractional deformation to the Pyrenean orogen building. 32nd Internation Geological Congress. Florence, Italy, 2004</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<publisher><![CDATA[DIGITAL.CSIC]]></publisher>
	
	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="contactPerson"><![CDATA[Díaz, J.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="projectLeader"><![CDATA[Gallart Muset, Josep]]></contributor></contributors>	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Díaz, J.]]></contributor></contributors>
		
	<creators>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Gallart Muset, Josep]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Pulgar, J. A.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Muñoz, Josep A.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Diaz, J.]]></creatorName></creator>
	</creators>
	<titles>
		<title><![CDATA[ Lithospheric Structure of the Cantabrian Margin - Bay of Biscay (MARCONI) ]]></title>
	</titles>

	<date dateType="Issued">2019-10-14</date>
	
	<resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="dataset"/>
	
	<language>eng</language>
	
	<subjects><subject>Field</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Active:MCS</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>DigitalSeg</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SEGY</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Reflection</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Hydrophone_OceanBottom</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismometer_OceanBottomCable</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SeismicSource_Gun_Air</subject></subjects>
	
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Abstract"><![CDATA[MARCONI (MARgen COntinental NordIberico - North Iberian Continental Margin) is a deep seismic reflection survey carried out in the southeastern part of the Bay of Biscay in September 2003. It included the acquisition of 11 multichannel deep seismic reflection profiles covering a total length of 2000 km. The overall goal of the multichannel experiment was to collect seismic data to unravel the structure and evolution of the southern margin of the Bay of Biscay in relation to the Mesozoic tectonic extension and collision and inversion of extensional faults in the context of the Alpine orogeny.]]></description></descriptions>	                            
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Description"><![CDATA[The total amount of seismic data were 11 profiles N-S, E-W and NW-SE oriented raging between 70 and 250 km. The signal was recorded in a network of 24 OBS/OBH instruments and 36 land stations. Technical specifications of the profiles: Streamer length: 2400 m; Group numer: 96; Group interval: 25 m; Source: air guns; Record length: 18 s; Sample rate: 4 ms.]]></description></descriptions>                    
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Ministerio de Ciencia y Tecnología (España)</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>

	<geoLocations><geoLocation><geoLocationPlace><![CDATA[Southeastern part of the Bay of Biscay. Bounding box (westBoundLongitude= -6 ; eastBoundLongitude= -2; southBoundLatitude= 43.5; northBoundLatitude= 46)]]></geoLocationPlace></geoLocation></geoLocations>	
</resource>
