<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4.1/metadata.xsd">
		
	<identifier identifierType="DOI">10.20350/digitalCSIC/8549</identifier>
	<rightsList><rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"/></rightsList>
	<alternateIdentifiers><alternateIdentifier alternateIdentifierType="Handle">http://hdl.handle.net/10261/167231</alternateIdentifier></alternateIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Torne, Montserrat; Banda E.; Sibuet, J.C.; Mendes-Victor, L.; Senos, M.L.; Long, R.,  Watts, A. B., Iberian Atlantic Margins (IAM project), Report, DIGITAL.CSIC, https://digital.csic.es/handle/10261/167037, http://dx.doi.org/10.20350/digitalCSIC/8566</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	
	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="contactPerson"><![CDATA[Torne, Montserrat]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="hostingInstitution"><![CDATA[Seismic Laboratory CSIC-ICTJA]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Torne, Montserrat]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Banda, E.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Sibuet, J.C.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Mendes-Victor, L.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Senos, M. L.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Long, R.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Watts, A. B.]]></contributor></contributors>
		
	<creators>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Torné, Montserrat]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Banda, E.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Sibuet, J. C.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Mendes-Victor, L.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Senos, M. L.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Long, R.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Watts, A. B.]]></creatorName></creator>
	</creators>
	<titles>
		<title><![CDATA[ Multichannel seismic reflection and wide-angle and refraction data acquisition along the Iberia Atlantic Margins ]]></title>
	</titles>

	<date dateType="Issued">2018-06</date>
	
	<resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="dataset"/>
	
	<language>eng</language>
	
	<subjects><subject>field</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>processed</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Active:MCS</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Reflection</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Refraction</subject></subjects>
	
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Abstract"><![CDATA[The Iberian Atlantic Margins (IAM) project is a multinational research programme, coordinated by the Institute of Earth Sciences of Barcelona, CSIC (Spain). It involves different academic institutions of Britain (University of Oxford and University of Durham), France (IFREMER), Portugal (University of Lisbon and Institute of Meteorology of Lisbon) and Spain (Institute of Earth Sciences of Barcelona, CSIC) and more than 40 associated scientists of European institutions attached to the main contractors. The project, financed by the European Community within its JOULE-Programme (Contract# JOU2-CT92-0177), aims to explore the deep continental and oceanic Atlantic margins of Iberia for a better understanding of the formation and evolution of Atlantic type margins, outstanding structural features and potential location of hydrocarbons and other natural resources. The project was designed to acquire deep seismic multichannel data and onshore recording of wide angle and refraction data along the North Iberian margin; the West Iberia margin, including the Galicia margin, the Iberia and Tagus abyssal plain, and the continental shelf off Portugal; and the Gorringe Bank region and Gulf of Cadiz. The experimental part of the study consisted of the acquisition of over 3700 km of near vertical incidence deep seismic multichannel reflection data. This together with wide angle reflection and refraction data recorded by land stations and OBS (Ocean Bottom Seismometers) has resulted in a full coverage in terms of crustal structure and velocity information of the study region.]]></description></descriptions>	                            
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Description"><![CDATA[The data acquisition contract was awarded to GECO-PRAKLA and took place in August-September 1993 aboard M/V Geco Sigma. Seismic data was successfully collected along the Cantabrian Margin, Galicia Margin, Iberian Abyssal Plain, the continental platform of Western Iberia, Tagus Abyssal Plain, the Gorringe Bank and Gulf of Cadiz. Data for the 240 km long line IAM-12 was acquired in February 1993 by SEISQUEST vessel of GECO-PRAKLA. The total amount of seismic reflection data collected was 3808.175 km in 19 track lines offshore. Technical specifications of the profiles: Streamer length 4800 m, Number of channels 192, Group interval 25 m, Shotpoint interval 75 m (100 m and 150 m on line IAM-2W), Source 7424 in3 (Record length 25 seconds), Sample rate 4 ms. Contact person: Torne, M., mtorne@ictja.csic.es.]]></description></descriptions>                    
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>European Commission</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>

	<geoLocations><geoLocation><geoLocationPlace><![CDATA[Name=North Iberian margin (Cantabrian), Western Iberian margin, Gorringe Bank, Gulf of Cadiz]]></geoLocationPlace></geoLocation></geoLocations>	
	<geoLocations><geoLocation><geoLocationPlace><![CDATA[lat=min 35.0000, max 46.0000; long=min -6.0000, max -14.0000]]></geoLocationPlace></geoLocation></geoLocations>	
</resource>
