<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4.1/metadata.xsd">
		
	<identifier identifierType="DOI">10.20350/digitalCSIC/9018</identifier>
	<rightsList><rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"/></rightsList>
	<alternateIdentifiers><alternateIdentifier alternateIdentifierType="Handle">http://hdl.handle.net/10261/193986</alternateIdentifier></alternateIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ehsan, S. A. (2014). Seismic characterization of the Central Iberian Zone from the surface to the upper mantle. PhD Thesis</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell, R., Levander, A., and Kind, R. (2013). TheMohorovičić discontinuity beneath the continental crust: An overview of seismic constraints. Tectonophysics 609, 353-376.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Brown, D., Zhang, X., Palomera, I., Simancas, F., Carbonell, R., Juhlin, C., and Salisbury, M. (2012). Petrophysical analysis of a mid-crustal reflector in the IBERSEIS profile, SW Spain. Tectonophysics, vol. 550-553, pp. 35-46.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Martínez Poyatos, D., Carbonell, R., Palomeras, I., Simancas, J. F., Ayarza, P., Martí, D., Azor, A., Jabaloy, A., González Cuadra, P., Tejero, R., Martín Parra, L.M., Matas, J., González Lodeiro, F., Pérez-Estaún, A., García Lobón, J. L., and Mansilla, L. (2012). Imaging the curstal structure of the Central Iberian Zone (Variscan Belt): The ALCUDIA deep seismic reflection transect. Tectonics, vol. 31, TC3017.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Palomeras, I., Carbonell, R., Ayarza, P., Fernàndez, M., Simancas, J.F., Martínez Poyatos, D., González Lodeiro, F., and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2011). Geophysical model of the lithosphere across the Variscan Belt of SW-Iberia: Multidisciplinary assessment. Tectonophysics 508, 42-51.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ayarza, P., Palomeras, I., Carbonell, R., Afonso, J.C., and Simancas, F. (2010). Physics of the Earth and Planetary Interiors 181, 88-102.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Palomeras, I., Carbonell, R., Flecha, I., Simancas, F., Ayarza, P., Matas, J., González-Lodeiro, F., and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2009). Nature of the lithosphere across the Variscan orogen of SW Ineria: Dense wide-angle reflection data. Journal of Geophysical Research, vol. 114, B02302, doi:10.1029/2007JB005050</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Flecha, I., Palomeras, I., Carbonell, R., Simancas, F., Ayarza, P., Matas, J., González-Lodeiro, F., and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2009). Seismic imaging and modelling of the lithosphere of SW-Iberia. Tectonophysics 472, 148-157.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ayarza, P., Palomeras, I., Simancas. F., Carbonell, R., Martínez-Poyatos, D., Azor, A., Pérez-Estaún, A., and González-Lodeiro, F.  (2008). An upper mantle reflector beneath SW Iberia. Location and seismic constraints. The 33rd International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, August 2008.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Palomeras, I., Fernández, M., Carbonell, R., Simancas. F., Ayarza, P., Martínez-Poyatos, D., Azor, A., González-Lodeiro, F., and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2008). A large seismic transect across the variscan belt of SW-Iberia: A multidisciplinary view. The 33rd International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, August 2008.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<publisher><![CDATA[DIGITAL.CSIC]]></publisher>
	
	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="projectLeader"><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></contributor></contributors>	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Palomeras, I.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Simancas, José Fernando]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Ayarza, P.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[González-Lodeiro, Francisco]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Pérez-Estaún, Andrés]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Azor, Antonio]]></contributor></contributors>
		
	<creators>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Palomeras, Imma]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Simancas, José Fernando]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Ayarza, P.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[González-Lodeiro, Francisco]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Pérez-Estaún, Andrés]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Azor, Antonio]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></creatorName></creator>
	</creators>
	<titles>
		<title><![CDATA[ Wide-angle deep seismic reflection profile (IBSERSEIS Wide-Angle Transect) ]]></title>
	</titles>

	<date dateType="Issued">2019-11-05</date>
	
	<resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="dataset"/>
	
	<language>eng</language>
	
	<subjects><subject>Field</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Active:MCS</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>DigitalSeg</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SEGY</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Reflection</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SeismicSource_Explosive</subject></subjects>
	
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Abstract"><![CDATA[The IBERSEIS wide-angle seismic reflection dataset consists of
two NE-SW oriented transects acquired in the SW of the Iberian Massif. They crossed three major geological zones (South Portuguese Zone, Ossa-Morena Zone, and Central Iberian Zone), with their tectonic contacts and the Pyrite Belt being of
greatest interest. The velocity models obtained by forward modeling show a complex crust, especially in the middle crust. The velocity models are the most detailed ones that have been produced in the area and contain a large amount of new features that are relevant to the understanding of the composition of the crust and upper mantle beneath the zone.]]></description></descriptions>	                            
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Description"><![CDATA[The wide-angle seismic reflection data set consists of two transects. Transect A coincides with the trace of the IBERSEIS deep seismic reflection profile and transect B is located farther to the SE. The explosive charge was located in a single 20 cm diameter, 50–60-m deep shothole. Explosive shots with charge sizes of 1000, 750 and 500 kg, where distributed along the transect, with the largest charges located at the edges of the profile.  650 digital seismic recorders (590 Texans and 60 3-component Refteks) from IRIS (Incorporated Research Institutions for Seismology) instrument pool where used. These instruments where placed along the 300-km transect A at a 400-m station spacing. For transect B, a denser trace spacing was used. To achieve this, shots were fired twice. The stations were firstly placed at 300–400 m spacing along transect B. Once the shots were fired, the stations were moved 150–200 m toward the north along the profile. All shots were then fired a second time, resulting in shot records with a 150–200 m trace spacing.]]></description></descriptions>                    
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Ministerio de Ciencia e Innovación (España)</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Generalitat de Catalunya</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Junta de Andalucía</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>

	<geoLocations><geoLocation><geoLocationPlace><![CDATA[Transect A: start point (pointLongiture= -7.3406; pointLatitude= 37.2586) and end point (pointLongiture= -5.0004; pointLatitude= 38.8248) and Transect B: start point (pointLongiture= -6.7023; pointLatitude= 37.4576) and end point (pointLongiture= -4.9994; pointLatitude= 38.8261)]]></geoLocationPlace></geoLocation></geoLocations>	
</resource>
