<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4.1/metadata.xsd">
		
	<identifier identifierType="DOI">10.20350/digitalCSIC/9016</identifier>
	<rightsList><rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"/></rightsList>
	<alternateIdentifiers><alternateIdentifier alternateIdentifierType="Handle">http://hdl.handle.net/10261/193954</alternateIdentifier></alternateIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ayarza, P., Carbonell,  R., Palomeras, I., Ehsan, S. A., Afonso, J. C., and Diaz, J. (2015). Mapping the Hales discontinuity in southwestern Spain. International Union of Geodesy and Geophysics. http://diposit.ub.edu/dspace/handle/2445/65254</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ehsan, S. A. (2014). Seismic characterization of the Central Iberian Zone from the surface to the upper mantle. PhD Thesis</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Simancas, J. F., Ayarza, P.,Azor, A., Carbonell, R., Martínez Poyatos, D., Pérez-Estaún, A.,and González Lodeiro, F. (2013). A seismic geotraverse across the Iberian Variscides: Orogenic shortening, collisional magmatism, and orocline development. Tectonics, vol. 32, 417-432. https://doi.org/10.1002/tect.20035</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell, R., Levander, A., and Kind, R. (2013). TheMohorovičić discontinuity beneath the continental crust: An overview of seismic constraints. Tectonophysics 609, 353-376. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tecto.2013.08.037</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Martínez Poyatos, D., Carbonell, R., Palomeras, I., Simancas, J. F., Ayarza, P., Martí, D., Azor, A., Jabaloy, A., González Cuadra, P., Tejero, R., Martín Parra, L.M., Matas, J., González Lodeiro, F., Pérez-Estaún, A., García Lobón, J. L., and Mansilla, L. (2012). Imaging the curstal structure of the Central Iberian Zone (Variscan Belt): The ALCUDIA deep seismic reflection transect. Tectonics, vol. 31, TC3017. https://doi.org/10.1029/2011TC002995</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Brown, D., Zhang, X., Palomera, I., Simancas, F., Carbonell, R., Juhlin, C., and Salisbury, M. (2012). Petrophysical analysis of a mid-crustal reflector in the IBERSEIS profile, SW Spain. Tectonophysics, vol. 550-553, pp. 35-46. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tecto.2012.05.004</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Palomeras, I., Carbonell, R., Ayarza, P., Fernàndez, M., Simancas, J.F., Martínez Poyatos, D., González Lodeiro, F., and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2011). Geophysical model of the lithosphere across the Variscan Belt of SW-Iberia: Multidisciplinary assessment. Tectonophysics 508, 42-51. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tecto.2010.07.010</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell, R., Simancas. F .,  Martínez-Poyatos, D., Ayarza, P., Palomeras, I., Jabaloy, A., Gonzalez, P., Tejero, R., Matas, J., Martín-Parra, L., Azor, A., González-Lodeiro, F., García­Lobón, L., Pérez-Estaún, A., and Mansilla, L. (2008). New constraints on crustal structure of the southern Iberian Variscaides from deep seismic reflection profiles (IBERSEIS, ALCUDIA Projects). The 33rd International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, August 2008. http://www.earthscrust.org.au/reports/large-scale-transects.html</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Palomeras, I., Fernández, M., Carbonell, R., Simancas. F., Ayarza, P., Martínez-Poyatos, D., Azor, A., González-Lodeiro, F., and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2008). A large seismic transect across the variscan belt of SW-Iberia: A multidisciplinary view. The 33rd International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, August 2008. http://www.earthscrust.org.au/reports/large-scale-transects.html</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ayarza, P., Palomeras, I., Simancas. F., Carbonell, R., Martínez-Poyatos, D., Azor, A., Pérez-Estaún, A., and González-Lodeiro, F.  (2008). An upper mantle reflector beneath SW Iberia. Location and seismic constraints. The 33rd International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, August 2008. http://www.earthscrust.org.au/reports/large-scale-transects.html</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Gaite, B., Palomeras, I., and Carbonell, R.  (2008). Deep seismic reflection transects within the iberian peninsula: A geophysical data base. The 33rd International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, August 2008. http://www.earthscrust.org.au/reports/large-scale-transects.html</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Schmelzbach, C., Simancas, J.F., Juhlin, C., and Carbonell, R. (2008). Seismic reflection imaging over the South Portuguese Zone fold-and-thrust belt, SW Iberia Journal of Geophysical Research, vol. 113, B08301. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-246X.2008.03937.x</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Schmelzbach, C., Juhlin, C., Carbonell, R., and Simancas, J.F. (2007). Prestack and poststack migration of crooked-line seismic reflection data: A case study from the South Portuguese Zone fold belt, southwestern Iberia. Geophysics, vol. 72 (2). https://doi.org/10.1190/1.2407267</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Flecha, I., Carbonell, R., Zeyen, H., Martí, D., Palomeras, I.,Simancas, F., and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2006). Imaging granitic plutons along the IBERSEIS profile. Tectonophysics 420, 37-47. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tecto.2006.01.019</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Andara Oropeza, E. A. (2003). Visualización del subsuelo poco profundo a lo largo del perfil IBERSEIS : Reprocesado de datos de sismica de reflexión. Tesina. Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Flecha, I. (2003). Visualització sı́smica mitjançant tècniques tomogràfiques. PhD Thesis, Universitat de Barcelona, ICTJA-CSIC. 136 p.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell, R., Simancas, F., Juhlin, C., Ayarza, P., González, F., Pérez-Estaún, A., and Plata, J. (2002). Iberseis: A Deep Seismic Reflection Image of A Variscan Transpresive Orogen. EGS XXVII General Assembly, Nice, 21-26 April 2002, abstract #2724</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell, R., Simancas, F., Juhlin, C., Ayarza, P., González, F., Pérez-Estaún, A., and Plata, J. (2001). IBERSEIS: a seismic reflection image of the Variscan orogen, SW Iberia. AGU Fall Meeting Abstracts. 82</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Pérez-Estaún, A., Simancas, J. F., González Lodeiro, F., Ayarza, P., Azor, A., Juhlin, C., Sáez, R., Almodóvar, G. R., and Carbonell, R.; 2001; "Deep high resolution seismic reflection profile IBSERSEIS NI: Migrated and stack files. [Dataset]";  DIGITAL.CSIC; http://dx.doi.org/10.20350/digitalCSIC/12643</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<publisher><![CDATA[DIGITAL.CSIC]]></publisher>
	
	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="projectLeader"><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></contributor></contributors>	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Pérez-Estaún, Andrés]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Simancas, José Fernando]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[González-Lodeiro, Francisco]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Ayarza, P.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Azor, Antonio]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Juhlin, C.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Sáez, R.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Almodóvar, G. R.]]></contributor></contributors>
		
	<creators>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Pérez-Estaún, Andrés]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Simancas, José Fernando]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[González-Lodeiro, Francisco]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Ayarza, P.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Azor, Antonio]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Juhlin, C.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Sáez, R.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Almodóvar, G. R.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></creatorName></creator>
	</creators>
	<titles>
		<title><![CDATA[ Deep seismic reflection profile (IBSERSEIS Normal Incidence Transect) ]]></title>
	</titles>

	<date dateType="Issued">2019-11-04</date>
	
	<resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="dataset"/>
	
	<language>eng</language>
	
	<subjects><subject>Field</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Active:MCS</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>DigitalSeg</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SEGY</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Reflection</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismometer_SingleFrequency</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SeismicSource_VibroseisTruck</subject></subjects>
	
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Abstract"><![CDATA[IBERSEIS Normal Incidence (IBERSEIS-NI) is a NE-SW oriented deep seismic reflection profile that provided for the first time a complete section at crustal scale of the Variscan Iberian Massif in the SW of Spain. This seismic profile samples three major tectonic terranes: the South Portuguese Zone, the Ossa-Morena Zone, and the Central Iberian Zone. These terranes show a distinctive seismic signature, as do the sutures separating them. Late strike-slip movements through crustal wedges are apparent in the seismic image and have strongly modified the geometry of sutures. The upper crust appears to be decoupled from the lower crust all along the seismic line, but some deformation has been accommodated at deeper levels. A sill-like structure is imaged in the middle crust as a 1–2 s thick and 175 km long high-amplitude conspicuous reflective band. It is interpreted as a great intrusion of mafic magma in a mid-crustal decollement. Taking into account surface geological data and the revealed crustal architecture, a tectonic evolution is proposed for SW Iberia which includes transpressional collision interacting during Early Carboniferous with a mantle plume. The Moho can be identified along the entire transect as subhorizontal and located at 10 to 11 s, indicating a 30–35 km average crustal thickness. Its seismic signature changes laterally, being very reflective beneath the South Portuguese Zone and the Central Iberian Zone, but discontinuous and diffuse below the Ossa Morena Zone.]]></description></descriptions>	                            
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Description"><![CDATA[IBERSEIS is a 303 km long deep seismic reflection profile. The transect was recorded in 56 days (from May to July 2001) using a 400 channel SERCEL 388 and five 22 Ton Vibroseis trucks. The asymmetric split spread configuration changed along the profile according to the dips of outcropping structures. To achieve a high resolution at shallow levels and to image steep dips, a 35 m station spacing and a 70 m Vibration Point interval was used with a high fold (60 in average). A relatively long sweep (20 s) was chosen to increase the source energy rather than increasing the number of sweeps per Vibration Point. The migrated and stack dataset derived from this raw data are available in http://hdl.handle.net/10261/220989]]></description></descriptions>                    
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Description"><![CDATA[IBSERSEIS NI: Migrated and stack files: http://dx.doi.org/10.20350/digitalCSIC/12643 ; http://hdl.handle.net/10261/220989]]></description></descriptions>                    
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Comisión Interministerial de Ciencia y Tecnología, CICYT (España)</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>European Commission</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Junta de Andalucía</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Empresa Nacional de Residuos Radiactivos (España)</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Swedish Research Council</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Instituto Geológico y Minero de España</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Ministerio de Ciencia y Tecnología (España)</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>

	<geoLocations><geoLocation><geoLocationPlace><![CDATA[Seismic profile from Villablanca, Andalucía (https://www.geonames.org/6358249/villablanca.html) to west of Castuera, Extremadura (https://www.geonames.org/6355901/castuera.html) to . Line coordenates: start at pointLongitude=-7.3412 pointLatitude=37.2704; end at pointLongitude=-5.5969 pointLatitude=38.7825]]></geoLocationPlace></geoLocation></geoLocations>	
</resource>
