<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4.1/metadata.xsd">
		
	<identifier identifierType="DOI">10.20350/digitalCSIC/9061</identifier>
	<rightsList><rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"/></rightsList>
	<alternateIdentifiers><alternateIdentifier alternateIdentifierType="Handle">http://hdl.handle.net/10261/194009</alternateIdentifier></alternateIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ehsan, S. A.,Carbonell,  R.,  Ayarza, P., Martí, D., Martínez Poyatos, D., Simancas, J. F., Azor, A., Ayala, C., Torné, M., and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2015). Lithospheric velocity model across the Southern Central Iberian Zone (Variscan Iberian Massif): The ALCUDIA wide-angle seismic reflection transect. Tectonics, 34, 535–554. http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/2014TC003661</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ayarza, P., Carbonell,  R., Palomeras, I., Ehsan, S. A., Afonso, J. C., and Diaz, J. (2015). Mapping the Hales discontinuity in southwestern Spain. International Union of Geodesy and Geophysics. http://hdl.handle.net/10261/148566</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Ehsan, S. A.,Carbonell,  R., Cembrowski, M., Martí, D., Gil, A., Marzan, I., Ayarza, P., Martínez Poyatos, D., Simancas, J. F., and Azor, A. (2014). Lithospheric Structure Along the Wide-Angle Seismic Reflection Transect of the Central Iberian Massif. Geophysical Research Abstracts, vol. 16, EGU2014-2915.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell,  R., Ehsan, S. A., Ayarza, P., Martínez Poyatos, D., Simancas, J. F., Azor, A.,  and Pérez-Estaún, A. (2014). From the Surface Topography to the Upper Mantle Beneath Central-Iberian-Zone. the Alcudia Seismic Experiments. American Geophysical Union, Fall Meeting. abstract id. T23B-4672</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell, R., Ehsan, S., Ayarza, P., Martí, D., Martínez Poyatos, D.,  Schimmel, M., Ruiz, M.,  Palomeras, I., Simancas, J. F.,  Azor, A., Jabaloy, A., González Cuadra, P., Tejero, R., Martín Parra, L.M., Matas, J., Gil, A., Simancas, F., and Azor, A. (2012). New Wide-Angle Seismic Reflection Data Across the Central Iberia Peninsula: The ALCUDIA-WA transect. American Geophysical Union, Fall Meeting 2012, abstract id. T23F-2739.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<publisher><![CDATA[DIGITAL.CSIC]]></publisher>
	
	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="projectLeader"><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></contributor></contributors>	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Pérez-Estaún, Andrés]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Ayarza, P.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Martínez Poyatos, D.]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Simancas, José Fernando]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Azor, Antonio]]></contributor></contributors>
		
	<creators>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Pérez-Estaún, Andrés]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Ayarza, P.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Martínez Poyatos, D.]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Simancas, José Fernando]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Azor, Antonio]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></creatorName></creator>
	</creators>
	<titles>
		<title><![CDATA[ Wide-angle deep seismic reflection profile (ALCUDIA Wide-Angle Transect) ]]></title>
	</titles>

	<date dateType="Issued">2019-11-05</date>
	
	<resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="dataset"/>
	
	<language>eng</language>
	
	<subjects><subject>Field</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Active:MCS</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>DigitalSeg</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SEGY</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Reflection</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismometer_SingleFrequency</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SeismicSource_Explosive</subject></subjects>
	
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Abstract"><![CDATA[The high-resolution, wide-angle seismic reflection experiment, ALCUDIA-WA, was acquired in 2012 across central Iberia, aiming to constrain the lithospheric structure and resolve the physical properties of the crust and upper mantle. The seismic transect, ca. 310 km long, crossed the Central Iberian Zone from its suture with the Ossa Morena Zone to the southern limit of the Central System mountain range.]]></description></descriptions>	                            
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Description"><![CDATA[The acquisition design included three lines of receivers, having a total length of ca. 350 km. The main line,  ALCUDIA-WA, is ca. 310 km long strikes NE-SW to NNE-SSW, it is approximately perpendicular to the structural grain. A 40 km long line of receivers that trends NNW-SSE was deployed perpendicular to the Central System (CS) mountain range. Over 900 TEXANS (single component, digital recording seismic station) from the IRIS-PASSCAL Instrument Pool were deployed from the northern boundary of the Ossa-Morena Zone to the alpine thrust representing the southern boundary of the CS. The entire ALCUDIA-WA survey had a nominal shot and receiver spacing of 70 km and 400m, respectively. Five explosive sources, each one consisting in 1 TM of explosive, were placed in ~55m deep single boreholes, providing a signal rich in high frequencies resulting in shot records characterized by high signal-to-noise ratio. For this reason, these data can be qualified as a high-resolution wide-angle data set.]]></description></descriptions>                    
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Ministerio de Ciencia e Innovación (España)</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>

	<geoLocations><geoLocation><geoLocationPlace><![CDATA[Transect start point (pointLongiture= -5.3132; pointLatitude= 38.1231) and end point (pointLongiture= -4.0407; pointLatitude= 40.4551)]]></geoLocationPlace></geoLocation></geoLocations>	
</resource>
