<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4.1/metadata.xsd">
		
	<identifier identifierType="DOI">10.20350/digitalCSIC/8636</identifier>
	<rightsList><rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"/></rightsList>
	<alternateIdentifiers><alternateIdentifier alternateIdentifierType="Handle">http://hdl.handle.net/10261/179856</alternateIdentifier></alternateIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Martí, D.; Marzán, I.; Sachsenhausen, J.; Ruiz, M.; Torné, M.; Mendes, M.; Carbonell, R. (2019) 3-D seismic travel-time tomography validation of a detailed subsurface model: the case study of the Záncara River (Cuenca, Spain). Solid Earth, 10, 177-192.  https://doi.org/10.5194/se-10-177-2019</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Marzán, I., Martí, D., Álvarez-Marrón, J., Lobo, A., Ruiz, M., Torné, M., and Carbonell, R. (2018). Detailed 3D subsurface geophysical model: data integration, multi-parameter inversion and statistical integrated interpretation: the case study of the Zancata River Basin (Cuenca, Spain). International Symposium on Deep Earth Exploration and Practices, Beijing, China. Acta Geologica Sinica Vol. 92, Supp. 1. https://doi.org/10.1111/1755-6724.14099</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell, R., Marzán, I., Martí, D., Lobo, A., Jean, K., and Álvarez-Marrón, J. (2016). Detailed 3D geophysical model of the shallow surface (Záncara River Basin, Iberian Peninsula). American Geoscience Union, Fall Meeting, NS33B-1974. http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2016AGUFMNS33B1974C</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Martí, D., Marzán, I., Kormann, J., Álvarez-Marrón, J., and Carbonell, R.,  (2016). Shallow subsurface 3-D seismic velocity structure (Záncara river basin, Iberian Peninsula). 17th International Seismix  (International Symposium on Deep Seismic Profiling of the Continents and their Margins) Symposium: 104. Scotland, United Kingdom. https://digital.csic.es/handle/10261/150411</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Marzán, I., Martí, D., Lobo, A., Kormann, J., Álvarez-Marrón, J., and Carbonell, R.,  (2016). Geophysical data integration for a joint interpretation in a shallow gypsiferous context. 17th International Seismix (International Symposium on Deep Seismic Profiling of the Continents and their Margins) Symposium: 107. Scotland, United Kingdom. http://digital.csic.es/handle/10261/149970</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Marzán, I., Martí, D., Lobo, A., Kormann, J., Álvarez-Marrón, J., and Carbonell, R.,  (2016). Interpretación conjunta de modelos de velocidad y resistividad 3D mediante clasificación estadística. Geotemas 16 (1): 507-510. ISSN 1576-5172. Sociedad Geológica de España, IX Congreso Geológico de España, Huelva. http://digital.csic.es/handle/10261/147678</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Martí, D., Marzán, I., Álvarez-Marrón, J., and Carbonell, R.  (2016). Testing & Validating: 3D seismic travel time tomography (detailed shallow subsurface imaging). Geophysical Research Abstracts Vol. 18: EGU2016-7836-1. https://digital.csic.es/handle/10261/150368</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Marzán, I., Martí, D., Lobo, A., Álvarez-Marrón, J. and Carbonell, R.  (2016). Seismics-electrics Joint Interpretation in a gypsiferous context. Geophysical Research Abstracts Vol. 18: EGU2016-8062-1. https://digital.csic.es/handle/10261/150482</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Kormann, J.A., Martí, D., Rodríguez, J. E., Marzán, I., Gutiérrez, N., Ferrer, M., Hanzich, M., de la Puente, J., Carbonell, R., Cela, J. M. and Fernández, S.  (2016). 3D elastic full waveform inversion - on land study case. 78th European Association of Geoscientists & Engineers (EAGE) Conference and Exhibition 2016, Tu SRS2 08. Viena, Austria. doi: 10.3997/2214-4609.201600831. http://hdl.handle.net/2117/87763.  https://doi.org/10.3997/2214-4609.201600831</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Martí, D., Marzán, I., Sachsenhausen, J., Álvarez-Marrón, J., Cienfuegos, I., and Carbonell, R.  (2015). High-resolution Seismic Characterization of the Shallow Subsurface Applied to Civil Engineering . 77th European Association of Geoscientists & Engineers (EAGE) Conference and Exhibition 2015, WS03-B01. Madrid.  https://doi.org/10.3997/2214-4609.201413471. http://www.earthdoc.org/publication/publicationdetails/?publication=81311</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Sendin Manchado, S.  (2015). Integrated 3D geophysical study of the shallow subsurface of the Zancara River Basin (Cuenca, Spain). Master Thesis, ICTJA-CSIC. http://digital.csic.es/handle/10261/140131</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Carbonell, R., Martí, D., Marzán, I., and  Álvarez-Marrón, J. (2015). Seismic tomography: exploring the shallow surface (case history studies). Invited Talk, Department of Geology, Kyungpook National University, Daegu, Korea.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Sachsenhausen, J., Martí, D., Marzán, I., Cienfuegos, I., Álvarez-Marrón, J., Carbonell, R., and Pérez-Estaún, A.  (2014). High-resolution 3D velocity model from seismic tomography in the Záncara river basin (Cuenca, Iberian Peninsula). 16th Edition of the Deep SEISMIX International Symposium on Multi-scale Seismic Imaging of the Earth's crust and Upper Mantle. Castelldefels, Barcelona.  https://doi.org/10.13140/2.1.4828.1923.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="isreferencedby">Sachsenhausen, J.  (2014). Determination of 3D velocity model through seismic tomography in the Záncara River Basin (Cuenca, Iberian Peninsula). Master Thesis.</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
	<publisher><![CDATA[DIGITAL.CSIC]]></publisher>
	
	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="contactPerson"><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="projectLeader"><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></contributor></contributors>	
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Marzán, Ignacio]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Martí, David]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Torné, Montserrat]]></contributor></contributors>
	<contributors><contributor contributorType="researcher"><![CDATA[Ruiz Fernández, Mario]]></contributor></contributors>
		
	<creators>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Marzán, Ignacio]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Martí, David]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Torné, Montserrat]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Ruiz Fernández, Mario]]></creatorName></creator>
		<creator><creatorName><![CDATA[Carbonell, Ramón]]></creatorName></creator>
	</creators>
	<titles>
		<title><![CDATA[ High resolution seismic characterization of the shallow subsurface of the Loranca Basin (Spain): high resolution 3D ]]></title>
	</titles>

	<date dateType="Issued">2014-01-30</date>
	
	<resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="dataset"/>
	
	<language>eng</language>
	
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Active:MCS-3D</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>DigitalSeg</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SEGY</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismic:Velocity</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>Seismometer_SingleFrequency</subject></subjects>
	<subjects><subject>SeismicSource_Accelerated weight drop</subject></subjects>
	
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Abstract"><![CDATA[A high-resolution seismic tomography survey was acquired to obtain a full 3-D P-wave seismic velocity image of the Záncara river basin (eastern Spain). The study area consists of lutites and gypsum from a Neogene sedimentary sequence. The project also targeted the geometry of the underground structure with emphasis on defining the lithological contacts but also the presence of cavities and faults or fractures. An extensive drilling campaign provided uniquely tight constraints on the lithology; these included core samples and wireline geophysical measurements. The analysis of the well log data enabled the accurate definition of the lithological boundaries and provided an estimate of the seismic velocity ranges associated with each lithology. The final joint interpreted image reveals a wedge-shaped structure consisting of four different lithological units. The study features the necessary key elements to test the travel time tomographic inversion approach for the high-resolution characterization of the shallow surface. In this methodological validation test, travel-time tomography demonstrated to be a powerful tool with a relatively high capacity for imaging in detail the lithological contrasts of evaporitic sequences located at very shallow depths, when integrated with additional geological and geophysical data.]]></description></descriptions>	                            
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Description"><![CDATA[The data acquisition contract was awarded to ENRESA and took place in January 2014. Seismic data was successfully collected in the Záncara river basin (Cuenca, Spain). This is a high-resolution seismic tomography survey to obtain a full 3-D P-wave seismic velocity image of the studied area. A regular and dense grid of 676 shots and 1200 receivers was used to image a 500 m x 500 m area of the shallow surface. A 240-channel system and a seismic source, consisting of an accelerated weight drop, were used in the acquisition. Half a million travel-time picks were inverted to provide the 3-D seismic velocity distribution up to 120 m depth. The 3-D survey was acquired in five swaths, each one consisting on five receiver lines, resulting in a total of 3380 shot gathers. Technical specifications of the profiles: Receiver number: 240, Receiver interval: 2 m, Source accelerated weightdrop: 250 kg, Source interval: 6 m, Sample rate: 1 ms, Record time: 4 s.]]></description></descriptions>                    
	<descriptions><description descriptionType="Description"><![CDATA[In this repository, in addition to the seismic 3DSurvey, a resistivity model (VICANAS_3D_Res_UTM30), a lithological model (VICANAS_3D_Vp_Res_Lito_UTM30), and a training set (VICANAS_Training_set) are available. In order to improve the geological interpretation of the seismic tomography, we integrated it with the resistivity model to build a 3D lithological model. To this aim, we created a new bi-parameter grid with Vp and Res values at each node. Then, we lithologically classified the nodes using supervised learning according to a training set extracted from the wells.]]></description></descriptions>                    
	<fundingReferences><fundingReferences><funderName>Empresa Nacional de Residuos Radiactivos (España)</funderName></fundingReferences></fundingReferences>

	<geoLocations><geoLocation><geoLocationPlace><![CDATA[Name= Villar de Cañas (Cuenca, Spain); Loranca Basin (Iberian Chain); https://www.geonames.org/2509526/villar-de-canas.html; Longitude=-2,56428; Latitude=39,7786]]></geoLocationPlace></geoLocation></geoLocations>	
</resource>
